[Music]
start with a right triangle
with legs of length a and b
and hypotenuse of length c
now draw an a plus b by a plus b square
we can fit four rotated copies of the
triangle
in the square like this
notice that the space in the square not
covered by the triangles
is a square of side length c therefore
this unshaded area is c squared
we can also move the same colored
triangles together
to form two different a by b rectangles
now the unshaded area is given by an a
by a square
and a b by b square so that the unshaded
area
is a squared plus b squared consequently
we have seen that c squared must be
equal to a squared plus b
squared this is the pythagorean theorem